&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt;  好的
Now -- thank you very much and
那么谢谢大家
welcome.
欢迎大家
And my name is David Hayward,
我叫 David Hayward
and I'm really excited to talk
特别开心今天能来
to you today about all the great
为大家介绍我们为
new features and functionality
iOS macOS tvOS 上的
we've added to Core Image on
Core Image 框架新添的
iOS, macOS, and tvOS.
出色特性和功能
We have a great agenda today.
我们今天的内容很充实
I'll be giving a brief overview
我会带大家简要回顾一下
of Core Image and a summary of
Core Image
the highlights of what we've
概括一下我们今年
added this year.
新加入的一些要点
Then after that we'll spend the
然后我们会用
rest of the hour going into deep
剩余时间深入了解
details on all our new APIs and
所有新 API 和
new features.
新特性的具体情况
So, with that in mind, let's
那么按照这个大纲
start going in.
让我们来进入正题
So a brief overview of Core
先是对 Core Image 的
Image.
简要回顾
In a nutshell, Core Image
简单说 Core Image 框架
provides a simple
提供一种简单易用的
high-performance API to apply
高性能 API 用来对图像
filters to images.
进行滤镜处理
These images can be used to
这些图像可被用来
adjust the color, adjust the
调整颜色调整几何属性
geometry, or perform complex
或者执行复杂的
reductions or convolutions.
切割或卷积
There are several tricks that
Core Image 会使用
Core Image uses to get the best
几种小技巧来实现
performance out of this because
这些操作的最佳效果
these filters can be combined in
因为这些滤镜可以组合
either simple chains like this
要么是通过简单的叠加
example here or in complex
就像上面这个例子
graphs.
要么是复杂图形
One of the tricks Core Image
Core Image 为了出色效果
does to get great performance is
使用的技巧之一
to support automatic tiling, and
就是支持自动平铺
this allows us to -- if an image
这让我们可以
is too big or there's too much
如果图像尺寸过大
memory that's going to be
或者需要大量内存
required to render a render
来渲染图像
graph, we can reduce our memory
我们就可以降低
footprint.
相应的内存占用
Another feature of this tiling,
平铺功能的另一个特点
which it means that if we're
意味着如果我们只需
only rendering part of an image
渲染图像的一部分
we can be very efficient and
这样做的效率会很高
only load the portion of the
只需要加载我们需要的
input image that's needed.
图像的相应部分
So these are great performance
以上这些出众的性能
things that you get for free by
大家都可以免费享受
using Core Image.
只需要使用 Core Image
Also when you're writing your
此外如果大家要在 Core Image 内
own kernels in Core Image, our
编写自己的内核
language extensions provide you
我们的语言扩展也能
the ability to get this
让大家以最低的难度
functionality for free with very
免费实现
little difficulty.
这项功能
Another thing to keep in mind is
还有一点也要记住
that all the filters in Core
Core Image 中的
Image may be based on one or
所有滤镜都基于
more kernels, either our
一个或多个内核
built-in kernels or custom
要么是内置内核
kernels.
要么是自定义内核
And another trick Core Image
Core Image 用来实现
uses to get great performance is
出色性能的另一个技巧
to concatenate these kernels
就是将这些内核
into programs.
全部并置到程序中
This allows Core Image to reduce
这能让 Core Image
the number of intermediate
减少中间缓存的
buffers, which allows us to
个数帮助我们
reduce our memory requirements
降低对内存的要求
and also improves image quality.
同时提高图像质量
So with that introduction
基于以上介绍
underway, I'm going to give a
我要为大家简要
brief description of what we've
讲解一下我们今年
added to Core Image this year.
为 Core Image 添加的功能
It falls into three main
这些功能可以分为
categories.
三大类别
First, of course, is
首先当然就是
performance.
性能
As always, this is something
在任何时候这一点
that's very important to Core
对于 Core Image 来说
Image, and we've added some
都十分重要我们也在
enhancements in this area to
这方面做了些加强
give your application the best
让大家能够获得
performance.
最佳的性能
Specifically -- the next thing
我要提到的
I'd like to mention is that
第二点也是我们
we've also spent a lot of time
今年花了很多时间
this year enhancing Core Image
来加强的 Core Image 特性
to give you, the developer,
好让各位开发者大家
better information about how
更好地获知 Core Image
Core Image works internally.
内部运行情况的信息
All of these optimizations we do
我在前面几页中
internally that I alluded to in
提到的我们所做的
the previous slides, you can now
所有这些优化
see what we're doing to achieve
大家都可以看到
these.
我们是如何做到的
Thirdly, we've added a lot of
第三点我们添加了
functionality, and this is to
许多功能这是为了
allow your applications to get
能让大家的应用程序
the best access to all the new
以最轻松的方式利用
features on our platform.
我们平台上的所有新特性
So a little bit more detail on
那么再来更详细地
these.
解释一下这三点
In the area of performance, Core
在性能方面
Image now allows you to write CI
Core Image 如今可让大家
kernels directly in Metal.
直接使用 Metal 编写 CI 内核
And we also have a new API to
我们还推出了一款新的 API
allow you to better render to
能让大家更好地
destinations.
渲染目标 (destination)
We'll be talking about this in
我们稍后再来
much more detail later on in the
具体讲解其中的
presentation.
更多细节
In the area of information, we
信息方面
have a new API that allows you
我们推出了一款新的 API
to get information about what
可让大家获知 Core Image
Core Image did for a given
处理给定渲染程序
render.
的相关信息
And also, we have some great new
此外我们还新增了
Xcode Quick Look support, which
对 Xcode Quick Look 的出色支持
we'll show you.
稍后会展示给大家看
And in the area of
接下来是
functionality, we have some
功能方面我们也
great new stuff as well.
新增了些出色的功能
We have a new collection of
我们新增了一套
filters, new barcode support,
滤镜条形码支持
and also support for editing
还有对深度编辑的
depth.
支持
I want to call out the session
我想让大家回忆一下
that occurred earlier today on
今天在前面的一个讲座里
image editing with depth.
提到的支持深度的图像编辑
If you didn't see it, you should
如果有人错过了
definitely go back and watch it.
请务必回去看一看
It goes into great detail about
里面十分详尽地讲解了
how to use Core Image to edit
如何使用 Core Image
depth.
来编辑深度
So now let me talk in more
现在让我再来
detail about the new filters
更详尽地讲解一下
that we've added this release.
我们此次添加的新滤镜
We now have 196 built-in
现在我们总共有 196 种
filters, and we've added some
内置滤镜其中包括
that have been -- are great new
一些非常出色的
additions.
新滤镜
For example, some of these are
比如说其中有几种
very useful when you're working
在你处理深度数据时
with depth data.
会变得非常有用
For example, we have convenience
比如说我们为
filters for converting between
深度与视差之间的转换
depth and disparity.
提供了一些实用滤镜
We also have morphological
我们也提供了
operations, which allows you to
形态学处理可让大家
erode and dilate an image, which
对图像进行腐蚀和膨胀处理
is useful for manipulating depth
这在操作深度掩码时
masks.
非常有用
We also have convenience filters
我们还有一些实用滤镜
that allow you to combine an
可以让大家
image with two different color
基于图像深度使用
cubes based on the depth of an
两种不同的色彩立方体
image.
来合成图像
I also want to call out a great
我还想让大家回忆一下
new filter which we talk about
我们早先提到的一个
in the previous -- in the
很厉害的新滤镜
editing session called
是在图像编辑那场里
CIDepthBlurEffect, which allows
叫作 CIDepthBlurEffect
your application to get access
作用是让你能使用
to the great depth blur effect
出色的深度模糊效果
that we have in our camera and
就像我们在相机照片
photos application.
应用中所用的那种
Again, I highly recommend you
再说一次我还是要
watch the image editing and
强烈推荐大家去看看
depth session that was recorded
今天早些时候录制的
earlier today.
图像编辑与深度讲座
We also have several other new
我们也根据收到的
filters based on popular
强烈要求加入了
requests.
另外几种新滤镜
We have a filter now that allows
有一个滤镜
you to generate an image from
可让大家用文本
text, which is great for
生成图像很适合
allowing you to add watermarks
在给视频添加水印
to video or other textual
或其他文本覆层时
overlays.
使用
We have a filter that allows you
还有一款滤镜
to compare two images in
可让大家在 LabDeltaE 空间内
LabDeltaE space, which is great
对比两幅图像很适合
for seeing if your results are
用来查看编辑结果
what you expect or to give a
是否符合预期
user information about how much
或者让用户获取
an image might have changed.
图像修改程度的信息
We also have a new bicubic
我们也添加了新的
upsample, or downsample filter,
双立方上采样下采样滤镜
which is great for a variety of
非常适合多种
purposes.
用途的使用
We also have a new way of
我们还推出了一种
generating barcodes, which we'll
新的条形码生成方法
talk about in more detail later
我会在稍后
in the presentation.
更加详细地讲解
Lastly, in the area of filters,
最后滤镜方面
we have some filters that have
这次有一些滤镜
been improved since our last
相比上次发行
release.
做了一些改进
We have several of the blend
这次有几款
mode filters -- now behave more
混合模式滤镜
like expectations.
现在的效果更合乎期望
And we've also improved greatly
我们还大幅提高了
the quality of our demosaic and
去马赛克滤镜和
noise reduction filters that are
降噪滤镜的质量
part of our RAW pipeline.
这些都隶属于 RAW 图像处理
So, as we release new cameras,
我们推出新的相机
we'll be getting -- or support
我们也将
for new cameras, you'll see the
为新款相机提供支持
improvements of that.
届时大家将会看到这些改进
So that's new filters.
新滤镜的情况就是这样
I'd like to bring Tony up to the
现在我想请 Tony 上台
stage who'll be talking in
他将为大家详细讲解
detail about how to write
如何直接使用 Metal
kernels directly in Metal, which
来编写内核
is a great new feature.
这也是个很棒的新特性
&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt;  好的
Thank you David.
谢谢 David
Good afternoon everyone.
大家下午好
My name is Tony, and I'm really
我叫 Tony 真的很开心
excited to tell you about this
能来为大家讲解
great new feature we've added to
我们为 Core Image
Core Image.
添加的新特性
So let's get right to it.
让我们直接进入正题
So first, let's put this in a
首先让我们先来
little bit of context.
明确一下这个问题的语境
If you refer back to this simple
如果这里指的是
filter graph that you saw
我们刚才看到过的
earlier.
这张简单滤镜的图表
What we're talking about now are
我们现在所讲的
these kernels that you see here
就是这些内核大家可以
at the bottom, which allow you
在底部这里看到
to implement your very own
你可以用它来实现自己的
custom code that will describe
自定义代码代码内容
exactly how you want the pixel
就是精确描述你想在
to be processed on the GPU.
GPU 上执行的像素处理方式
So previously these kernels were
在以前这些内核
written in the CIKernel
都是使用 CIKernel 语言
Language, which was the shading
编写这是一种
language based on GLSL, but it
基于 GLSL 的着色语言
also provided some extensions
但它也提供一些扩展
that allows Core Image to enable
能让 Core Image 支持
automatic tiling and subregion
自动平铺和
rendering.
分区域渲染
For example, we had a function
举个例子我们有一个函数
called destCoord that lets you
叫作 destCoord
access the coordinate of the
能让你获得
destination that you are about
你准备渲染的
to render to regardless of
目标坐标
whether you're just rendering a
无论你是要渲染
subportion of the output or if
输出的一个区域
the output image is tiled.
还是要平铺输出图像
We also have a couple of
我们还有两个函数
functions called
分别叫作
samplerTransform and sample that
samplerTransform和sample
let you sample from an input
能让你对输入图像
image regardless of whether the
进行采样无论
input image is tiled.
输入图像是否经过平铺处理
So again, as David mentioned
所以就像 David
earlier, this provides a nice
之前提过的这能为
abstraction to tiling so that
平铺操作提供妥善的抽象化
you don't have to worry about
让你在编写你的
that when writing your kernels.
内核时不用为此烦心
So once these kernels are
当这些内核
written, they are then
编写完毕后它们会
translated, concatenated
接着经过转译
together as much as possible
尽可能多地与其他内核
with other kernels, and then
并置在一起然后
compiled at runtime to either
在运行时被编译成
Metal or GLSL.
Metal 或者 GLSL
Now for a rich language like
对于 Metal 这样的
Metal, the compilation phase can
富语言编译阶段
actually take quite a long time
在运行时可能会
at runtime.
耗费很长的一段时间
And, in fact, in the worst case,
事实上在最坏情景下
if you're just rendering a very
如果你是要渲染
small input image - sorry,
一幅很小的输入图像...抱歉
rendering a very small image or
渲染一幅很小的图像
a relatively simple filter
或者相对简单的滤镜图表
graph, most of that time could
大部分的时间可能
actually be spent compiling
都会花在编译上
versus the actual rendering.
而非实际的渲染上
So to show you an example of
为了给大家看个例子
that, here's a case where on the
这里有个案例
very first render before any of
是在任何编译结果被写入
the compilation has been cached,
cache 前的第一次渲染时
you can see there's a lot of
大家可以看到有大量时间
time spent compiling versus
都花费在编译
rendering.
而非渲染上
So if we step through these
所以如果我们逐句
stage by stage, the first step
调试下这些步骤第一步
is to translate the CIKernels
是翻译这里蓝色显示的
shown in blue.
CIKernel
And the second stage is to
第二个步骤是
concatenate the CIKernels.
并置这些 CIKernel
And then we go through a phase
接下来这一步里
to compile the CIKernels to an
我们要把 CIKernel
intermediate representation,
编译成中间表示
which is independent of the
这个过程是
device.
独立于设备类型的
And then there's a final stage
然后是最后一步
to actually compile that IR to
要把中间表示编译成
GPU code to be executed on the
GPU 代码以便在
GPU.
GPU 上执行
So the problem here is that
这里的问题在于
concatenating CIKernels is
CIKernel 的并置
something that has been done
原本是在运行时
dynamically at runtime, so what
动态完成的如果我们
if we were to allow that stage
把这个过程放到编译后
to happen after the compilation?
再来完成会是什么结果呢
So what that allows us to do is
结果就是让我们能够
hoist up that really expensive
将成本非常高的
compilation at build-time and
编译过程提到构建时完成
therefore leaving behind only
最后只留下那些
the work that needs to be done
需要在运行时
at runtime.
完成的部分
So, as you can see, this is now
大家可以看到
a much more efficient use of the
这样做对 CPU 的
CPU, not to mention lower power
利用要高效很多不用说
consumption.
耗电量也会减少
So I'm pleased to say that this
所以我要很高兴地告诉大家
is now possible in Core Image
Core Image 现在也能这么做了
and that's by writing CIKernels
只要直接使用 Metal
directly in Metal.
编写 CIKernel 就好
And to make this happen required
为了实现这一点需要我们
some really close collaboration
与 Metal 框架的开发团队
with both the Metal Framework
和 Metal 编译器的开发团队
Team and the Metal Compiler
展开十分密切的
Team.
合作
And we think this is going to
我们认为这样做
open up doors to some really
将会打开新的大门
exciting new opportunities.
迎来令人兴奋的新机遇
But first, let me just highlight
首先我要特别讲几个
some of the key benefits that
大家现在已经感受到的
you're already getting today.
主要优点
So, as you saw earlier, now the
就像之前看到的
CIKernels can be precompiled
CIKernel 现在已支持
offline at build-time.
在构建时进行离线预编译
And along with that, you can get
有了这项功能
some really nice error
你就能很方便地
diagnostics.
进行出错诊断
So if you had some typo or a
如果你在编写内核时
mistake in your kernel, you can
拼错了单词或者出了什么错
see that directly in Xcode,
都能直接在 Xcode 中看到
without having to wait for the
而不必等到运行时
runtime to detect them.
才检测出问题
Second is now you have access to
第二点则是添加了
much more modern language
更多的现代语言支持
features since Metal is a
因为 Metal 就是一种
relatively new language that was
近几年才问世的
based on C++.
基于 C++ 的语言
And I want to stress that with
我还想强调一点
writing CIKernels in Metal, you
用 Metal 编写 CIKernel 时
still get all the benefits such
大家照样能够享受
as concatenation and tiling,
并置平铺这些优点
which has been the cornerstone
这也是多年来
of our Core Image framework for
我们为 Core Image 框架
many years.
做出的重大突破
So nothing is compromised by
所以改用现在的
writing CIKernels in this new
新方法编写 CIKernel
way.
不会带来任何损失
And furthermore, these new
另外这些用 Metal
CIKernels in Metal can also be
写成的新 CIKernel
mixed with traditional
也可以与旧版的
CIKernels.
CIKernel 一起混用
So [inaudible] can contain
所以在今后的图像中
either traditional kernels or
既可以包含旧版的内核
kernels written in Metal.
也可以包含 Metal 写成的内核
And that allows this feature to
这能让这项新特性
be maximally compatible with
与大家现有的应用程序
your existing application.
实现最大兼容
And, as you would expect, this
大家可能也希望
feature is supported in a wide
这项特性能够得到
variety of platforms, namely iOS
各类平台的广泛支持也就是
for A8 or newer devices, as well
支持 A8 或更新版本的 iOS
as macOS and tvOS.
还有 macOS 和 tvOS
So now let's take a look at how
现在我们来看一下
we go about creating these Metal
到底要如何用 Metal
CIKernels.
创建这些 CIKernel
The first step is to write your
第一步就是用 Metal 着色文件
CIKernel in a Metal shader file.
来编写你的 CIKernel
Then once you have that CIKernel
接着在你完成这个 CIKernel 的
implemented, the second step is
实现后第二步就是
to compile and link the Metal
编译和链接 Metal 着色文件
shader file in order to generate
以便生成相应的 Metal 库
a Metal library that can then be
可在运行时
loaded at runtime.
进行加载
And then a final step is to just
接着最后一步就是
initialize the CIKernel with any
用 Metal 库内的任何函数
function from that Metal
对 CIKernel 进行
library.
初始化
So let's take a closer look at
那么我们来具体地
the first step, writing a
看下第一步
CIKernel in Metal.
用 Metal 编写 CIKernel
So to do that, I'd like to
对于这项任务我要向
introduce you to our new
大家介绍我们新推出的
CIKernal Metal library.
CIKernal Metal 库
And what that is is basically a
它基本上就是一个
header file that contains our
头文件包含我们为
CIKernel extensions to the Metal
Metal 着色语言添加的
shading language.
CIKernel 扩展
So namely we have some new data
换句话说我们加入了一些
types, such as destination,
新的数据类型比如目标 (destination)
sampler, and sample.
采样器 (sampler) 样本 (sample)
Destination lets you access all
目标类型可让你获得
the information that you need
你需要的有关输出的
that pertains to the output.
所有信息
And sampler lets you access all
采样器类型可让你获得
the information that pertains to
有关输入图像的
the input image.
所有信息
And sample is a representation
样本类型则用来表示
of a single-color sample from an
输入图像中的某个
input image.
单色样本
And along with these types we
除了这些数据类型外
also have some convenience
我们也添加了一些
functions that are very useful
实用函数非常方便
for image processing.
图像处理使用
For example, you can do
比如说你可以进行
premulitply and unpremultiply,
预乘 (premulitply) 去预乘 (unpremultiply)
as well as some color
还可以进行不同
conversions between different
色彩空间之间的
color spaces.
一些色彩转换
So these new extensions are
所以这些新扩展的
semantically the same as they
语义与它们用在
used to be in the CIKernel
CIKernel 语言中的时候
language.
是一样的
There's just some slight syntax
只是在涉及目标和
differences that pertains to the
采样器类型时稍微存在
destination and sampler types,
一点语法上的差异
so let me show you that in a
让我来给大家
little bit more detail.
看个更具体的例子
So here's a snippet of what our
这里有一小段代码
CIKernel Metal library looks
我们的 CIKernel Metal 库
like.
看起来就是这样
It is called CIKernelMetalLib.h,
库的名字是 CIKernelMetalLib.h
and all our extensions are
我们所有的扩展
declared inside a namespace
都在 CoreImage 这个
called coreimage to avoid any
命名空间中加以声明
conflicts with Metal.
以免与 Metal 发生冲突
So the first step that we have
这里的第一步就是
defined is called a destination
定义一个目标
and it has a method that lets
它包含一个函数
you access the coordinate of the
可让你用来读取
destination.
目标的坐标
Previously, if you were writing
在以前使用 CIKernel 语言
CIKernels in the CIKernel
编写 CIKernel 内核的时候
language, you would have done
只能通过一个叫作
that via a global function
destCoord 的全局函数
called destCoord.
来完成
But now, if you're writing
而现在使用 Metal 语言
kernels in Metal, you need to
编写内核的话
declare this type as an argument
只需要将这个数据类型
to your kernel in order to
声明为内核的实参
access that method.
就能访问这个方法
And then the second type we have
接下来要定义的
to find is the sampler.
第二种数据类型是 sampler
And this has all the same
它所包含的方法就是以前
methods that used to exist as
那些同名的全局函数
global functions, but they are
但它们现在被定义成了
now implemented as member
sampler 类型的
functions on the sampler type.
成员函数
So to give you a nice summary of
为了更好地概括
all that, here's a table that
这些函数这里有个表格
shows you the syntax that used
能让大家看到过去在
to exist in CIKernel language
CIKernel 语言里使用的语法
versus the syntax that is now
和如今在 Metal 里
available in Metal.
使用的语法
And, as you can see, in the
大家还可以看到
CIKernel language, those are all
在 CIKernel 语言中所有函数
implemented as global functions,
全用全球函数的方式来实现
but now with Metal, those are
而现在在 Metal 中它们
all member functions on their
全都会被定义为相应
appropriate types.
数据类型的成员函数
So we think that with the new
所以我们认为
syntax they'll allow you to
这种新语法将能让
write your code to be more
大家把代码写得
concise and easier to read.
更简明更易读
But for sake of portability, we
出于可移植性的考虑
did include the global sampler
我们也在头文件中
functions in our header, which
包含了 sampler 的全局函数
are merely just wrappers to the
实质上就是把新语法
new syntax.
封装了一下
So that'll help minimize the
这样一来就能让大家
amount of code changes that you
只需要修改最少的代码
need to make if you're importing
就能将已有的内核
from existing kernels to Metal.
导入到 Metal 中
So now let's take a look at some
现在我们来看几个用 Metal
examples of CIKernels in Metal.
编写的 CIKernel 例子
The first one we're going to
我们看到的第一个例子
look at is a warp kernel.
是一个 warp 内核
And as with all Metal shaders,
在编写任何 Metal 着色器时
the first thing you need to
需要引入的第一个库
include is the metal underscore
就是 metal_stdlib
stdlib, but for CIKernels you
而在编写 CIKernel 时
need to include our Metal kernel
还需要引入我们的 Metal
library, and that can be done by
内核库具体方法
just including an umbrella
就是引入一个综合头文件
header CoreImage.h. Then the
CoreImage.h 接下来
next step is to implement all
第二步是在
your kernels inside the extern C
Extern “C" 这个部分中
enclosure, and what that allows
实现你要的所有内核它的作用
is for the kernel to be
是让这些内核可以在运行时
accessible at runtime by name.
通过名称来访问
So here we have a simple kernel
这里写的是一个简单的内核
called myWarp.
叫作 myWarp
And all it takes is a single
它只需要一个实参
argument, a destination type,
数据类型为 destination
and from that destination you
根据这个实参
can access the coordinate that
你便可以获取
you're about to render to and
有待执行渲染
apply various geometric
和实现你想看到的
transformations that you want to
各种几何变换的
it.
相应坐标
And then return the result.
然后返回执行的结果
And for sake of comparison,
作为对比
here's that same warp kernel
这里也有一个同样的
that was implemented in the
warp 内核不过是用
CIKernel language.
CIKernel 语言实现的
So you can see they're almost
大家可以看到这两段代码
identical minus some minor
几乎完全相同只有一些
syntax differences.
细微的语法差异
But semantically they are the
但它们的语义是
same, and at the end of the day
完全相同的到最后
compiled to the exact same GPU
也都会被编译成一模一样的
code.
一段 GPU 代码
The second example here is a
第二个例子是个
color kernel.
color 内核
And for the most part it looks
它的大部分代码
very similar, the only
看上去都差不多
difference is now we have a
唯一的区别就是换成了
kernel called myColor, and what
一个叫作 myColor 的内核
it takes is a single sample as
它的输入只需要一个
input.
sample 类型的实参
From that sample, you can apply
根据这个实参你可以应用
various color transformations
你想要看到的
that you want on it and again
各种色彩变换最后
return the result.
同样是返回执行结果
Here again is that same color
那么这里同样是
kernel implemented in the
用 CIKernel 语言实现的
CIKernel language.
同一个 color 内核
And then the last example I want
我想给大家看的
to show you is a general kernel,
最后一个例子是个通用内核
which you can do if you can't
可以在你的内核既不能用
implement your kernel as either
warp 内核也不能用 color 内核
a warp or a color.
实现的时候使用
And so here we have a kernel
所以这里有这样一个内核
called myKernel.
叫作 myKernel
And it takes a single input,
它只需要一个输入参数
which is a sampler type, and
数据类型是 sampler
from that sampler, you can
根据这个参数你就可以对
sample anywhere in the input
输入图像的任意部位采样
image and take as many samples
根据你的需要获取
as you need.
足够数量的样本
And again, do something
同样在这里
interesting with it and return
执行一些操作
the result.
返回执行结果
And one more time, here is that
同样这个是
same CIKernel written in the old
用以前的 CIKernal 语言
CIKernal language.
写成的同一个 CIKernal 内核
So now that you have a CIKernel
现在你已经在 Metal 着色文件中
implemented in Metal shader
完成了 CIKernal 的实现
file, the next step is to
下一步就是
compile and link the Metal
编译和链接 Metal
shader.
着色文件
So, for those who have
对于有过 Metal 着色器
experience writing Metal
编写经验的人来说
shaders, this build pipeline
这套构建管道看起来
should look very familiar.
应该十分眼熟
It's basically a two-stage
基本上它分为
process.
两个阶段
The first one is compiling a
第一个阶段是
.metal to a .air file, and then
将.metal 编译成.air 文件
the second stage is to link the
第二个阶段是
.air file, and package it up in
链接.air 文件然后把它
a .metallib file.
打包在.metallib 文件里
The only additional thing you
处理 CIKernel 时只需要
need to do here for CIKernels is
在这里多做一件事
specify some new options.
就是设定几个新的选项
The first option you need to
第一个需要设定的选项
specify is for the compiler.
是针对编译器的
It is called -fcikernel.
叫作-fcikernel
And then the second option is
第二个选项是
for the linker and it's called
针对链接器的
-cikernel.
叫作-cikernel
Note that there's no f on that
注意这个选项
option.
就是少了个 f
And you can do that directly in
你可以直接在 Xcode 里
Xcode, and let me show you that
完成这一步让我用
with a short little video clip
一段小视频给大家演示一下
that illustrates how that can be
这个步骤是如何
done.
完成的
So for the compiler option, you
对于编译器选项
could just look up the Metal
只需要查看 Metal 编译器的
compiler build options and
Build Options 然后直接在
specify -fcikernel directly in
Other Metal Compiler Flags 中
the other Metal compiler flags.
写明-fcikernel 即可
And because we don't have a UI
由于链接器选项没有
for linker options to specify
这种界面来进行相关设置
that, you have to add a
必须使用
user-to-find setting.
Add User-Defined Setting
And give that setting a key
然后为它设置一个键
called MTLLINKER underscore
命名为 MTLLINKER_FLAGS
FLAGS and then the value that
然后将对应的值
you specify is -cikernel.
设定为 -cikernel
So you just need to set this up
你只需要为你的项目
once for your project.
设置一次
And then all the Metal shaders
之后你在这里处理的
that you have in there will be
所有的 Metal 着色器都会
automatically compiled with
自动使用这些选项
these options.
进行编译
But if you prefer to do things
但如果你更喜欢使用
on [inaudible] or in a custom
或者自定义脚本来处理
scrip, you can also invoke those
同样可以调用这两个
two compiler and linker tools,
编译器和链接器工具
like so.
就像这样
So now the last and probably the
那么最后一步大概也是
easiest step is to initialize a
最简单的一步就是使用
CIKernel with a given function
Metal 库中的给定函数
from the Metal library.
对 CIKernel 进行初始化
And so to do that we have some
为此我们为 CIKernel 类
new API on our CIKernel class,
加入了新的 API
and they allow you to initialize
可以让你使用通过函数名
the CIKernel with a given
调用的给定函数以及
function by name as well as a
可在运行时予以
Metal library that you can load
加载的 Metal 库
at runtime.
来初始化 CIKernel
There's also a variant on this
这个 API 还有一个变种
API that lets you specify an
能让你为你的内核
output pixel format for your
指定一种
kernel.
输出像素格式
So if your kernel is just going
如果你的内核只是要
to output some single shadow
输出一些单一阴影数据
data, you can specify a single
你完全可以为内核
shadow format for that kernel.
指定一种单一阴影格式
So here's an example of how to
这里有个例子来演示
initialize the CIKernel.
CIKernel 的初始化
All it takes is those three
总共只需要
simple lines.
这么三行代码
The first two is for loading the
前两行用来
Metal library, which, by
加载库如果是
default, if it was built in
在 Xcode 内构建的
Xcode, will be called
会默认调用
default.metallib.
default.metallib
And then once you have that data
而在完成数据加载后
loaded, you can initialize the
便可以用这个库中的
CIKernel with a given function
给定函数名来
name from that library.
初始化 CIKernel 了
Similarly, for warp and color
同样 warp 和 color 内核
kernels they can be initialized
可以用同样的 API
with the exactly the same API.
来完成初始化
So once you have that kernel
在完成内核初始化后
initialized you can apply that
你就可以用自己喜欢的方式
however you like to produce the
应用这个内核生成
filter graph that you desire.
你想要的滤镜图像
So that's all there is to
以上就是使用 Metal
writing CIKernels in Metal and
编写 CIKernel 的所有内容
we think this is going to be a
我们认为这会为开发者
great new workflow for
新建出很好的工作流
developers so we look forward to
很期待大家能利用这些
seeing some amazing things that
新性能做出一些
you can do with this new
令人惊艳的
capability.
产品来
All right.
好的
So now the next topic I'd like
那么下一个主题
to talk about is a new API that
我想讲讲我们用来
we have for rendering to
渲染目标的一种
destinations.
新的 API
And this is a new consistent API
这款新 API 应用在我们
across all the different
支持的所有 destination 类型时
destination types that we
都能给出一致统一的
support.
表现
Namely IOSurfaces, which, by the
它的名字叫 IOSurfaces
way, is now public API on iOS.
目前是 iOS 上的一款公共 API
And we also support rendering to
我们还支持渲染至
CVPixelBuffers, as well as Metal
CVPixelBuffer 以及 Metal 和
and OpenGL Textures.
OpenGL 纹理
Or even just some raw bitmap
甚至是内存中的
data that you have in memory.
某些原始位图数据
And one of the first things
这款 API 时首先让你
you'll notice with this new API
注意到的一点是
is that it will now return
如今它在检测到
immediately, if it detects a
渲染失败时会立即返回
render failure, and give you
并且回复给你
back an error indicating why it
一条出错消息表明
failed.
失败原因
So now you can actually detect
所以现在你可以通过程序
that programmatically in the
检测应用中的此类问题
application and fails gracefully
并在检测到出错时
if an error is detected.
有所准备地失败
With this API, you can also set
凭借这款 API 你还可以设定
some common properties for the
destination 对象的一些
destination object, such as an
常见属性例如行为是
alpha mode or a clamping mode
alpha 模式还是 clamping 模式
behavior, or even a colorspace
甚至可以是你想要用来
that you want to render the
渲染输出的
output to.
色彩空间
Previously, with our existing
以前在使用旧式的
API, the alpha mode and clamping
API 时 alpha 模式和
mode was something that would be
clamping 模式
determined implicitly, based on
都是通过隐晦的方式设定
the format of your destination.
基于目标所用的格式
But now, you can actually
而如今你完全可以
explicitly override that with
明确地使用你想要的
the behavior that you want.
行为进行重写
In addition to these common
除了这些常见属性外
properties, we have some new
我们还添加了几种
advanced properties that you can
新的高级属性
set on the destination, such as
可供你设置目标时使用
dithering and blending.
例如抖动 (dithering) 和混合 (blending)
So, for example, if you have an
举个例子如果你有一个
8-bit output buffer that you
8位的输出缓冲区
want to render to, you can just
并且打算用来渲染
simply enable dithering to get
那你只需要开启抖动
some -- a greater perceived
来获得某种感知范围
color depth in order to reduce
更广的色彩深度以便减少
some banding artifacts that you
可能会在图像
may see in certain parts of the
局部区域出现的
image.
一些色带瑕疵
And a nice thing about these
这些属性有一点
properties is now they
很不错就是
effectively reduce the need for
能够有效地降低
having to create multiple
被迫创建多个
CIContexts.
CIContext 的需要
And that's because some of these
这是因为这些属性中
properties used to be tied to
有的原本是 CIContext 的
the CIContexts.
附属属性
So, if you had multiple
所以当你需要
configuration of different
配置多个不同的
destinations, you would have had
目标时就必须
to create a CIContext for every
为每个目标单独
single one.
创建一个 CIContext
So now that these properties are
如今这些属性全都
nicely decoupled, you can, for
很好地剥离了出来
the most part, just have one
在大部分时候你都可以
CIContext that can render to
只用一个 CIContext 就能
various different destinations.
渲染出多个不同的目标
But along with all these
这款 API 不光提供了
functionality that this API
前面提到的所有
provides, there are some really
这些功能还可以用它
great performance enhancements
实现一些
that can be realized with this
特别出色的
new API.
性能增强
For example, our CIContext API
比如说我们的 CIContext API
for rendering to IOSurfaces or
在用来渲染到 IOSurface 或者
CVPixelBuffers.
CVPixelBuffer 时
They used to return after all
以前它们会在 GPU
the render on the GPU is
完成所有的渲染工作后
completed.
再返回执行结果
But now with this new API, it
但现在使用新的 API
will return as soon as the CPU
会在 CPU 将 GPU 的这些工作
has finished issuing all the
指令全部发送完毕后
work for the GPU.
就立即返回结果
And without having to wait for
再也不用等到
the GPU work to finish.
GPU 结束所有工作后了
So we think this new flexibility
所以我们认为这种新增的
will now allow you to pipeline
灵活性能让大家
all your CPU and GPU work much
更加高效地安排
more efficiently.
CPU 和 GPU 的所有工作
So let me show you an example of
现在让我来给
that use case.
大家看个使用实例
So here we have a simple render
这里是一个简单的
routine that is going to clear a
渲染子程序目的是
destination surface and then
清理出一个目标面
render a foreground image over
然后在背景图像上层
top of a background image.
渲染出前景图像
So the first thing we do is
我们要做的第一件事
initialize a CIRenderDestination
就是初始化一个 ioSurface 给定的
object given in ioSurface.
CIRenderDestination 对象
And then the first thing we want
然后我们想要的第一个结果
is to get a CIContext and start
则是获取一个 CIContext
a render task to clear the
启动渲染任务
destination.
清理目标
But before waiting for that task
但在等候这项任务
to actually finish, we can now
实际完成前我们就可以
start another task to render the
先启动另一项任务
background image to the
在目标处渲染
destination.
背景图像
And then, now before we start
然后在我们启动
the final task, we can set a
最后一项任务之前我们可以
blend kernel on this destination
为目标对象设定一个混合内核
object, which can be anyone of
可以从我们提供的 37 个内置的
our 37 built-in blend kernels.
混合内核中任选一个
In this case, we've chosen a
在这个例子里我们选了一个
sourceOver blend.
sourceOver 混合内核
But you can even create your own
但你还可以使用最新的
custom blend kernel by using our
CIBlendKernel API 创建
new CIBlendKernel API.
一个自定义的混合内核
So once we have the blend kernel
那么我们要的混合内核
that we want, we then call
也有了现在让我们来
CIContext to start the final
调用 CIContext 启动最后的
render task to render the
渲染任务在目标处
foreground image over top of
已有的任何结果
whatever is already in that
上层叠加渲染
destination.
前景图像
And only then do you need to
只有这个时候你才需要
call waitUntilCompleted, if you
调用 waitUntilCompleted
need to access the contents on
用它来获取 CPU 上的
the CPU.
内容
So with this new setup, this
所以通过这种新设计
will now minimize the latency of
能将获取结果的延迟时间
getting your results without
缩到最短还不用
having to do any unnecessary
执行任何不必要的
synchronization with the GPU.
GPU 同步指令
The next use case I'd like to
我要给大家看的
illustrate is one that will
第二个用例会特别
highlight a much more subtle
演示一下性能方面的
performance benefit, but it can
细微优势但这点优势
have a huge impact in your
却能为你的应用程序
application.
带来巨大影响
And that's rendering to Metal
那就是渲染到
drawable textures.
Metal 可绘制纹理
So you can do that very simply
这做起来很简单只要
by getting a currentDrawable
获取一个 currentDrawable
from, let's say Metal
就行比如说
[inaudible] view.
从 Metal 视图中获取
And then from that, you can
接下来便可使用
initialize a CIRenderDestination
可绘制视图中的纹理
with the texture from that
完成一 个CIRenderDestination 的
drawable.
初始化
So this will work just fine, but
这段程序就能达成我们的目的
if you were to do this in a
但如果你是在每帧渲染循环中
per-frame render loop, there's a
执行这样的任务却有可能
potential for a performance
遇到性能上的瓶颈
bottleneck here that may not be
而表面上可能
so obvious.
并不明显
So let me try to describe that
让我用一个时间轴图示
or explain that in a little bit
来更加详细地
more detail with a timeline view
描述解释一下
here.
这个情况
And please bear with me because
还请大家耐心听
there could be a lot of steps
因为这里面会涉及到
involved.
非常多的步骤
So here we have a timeline that
我们在这条时间轴上
has two tracks, the CPU at the
追踪两个对象上面是
top and the GPU at the bottom.
CPU 下面是 GPU
Technically there's actually a
严格来说这个过程里
third component in play here,
其实还存在一个第三方
which is to display.
也就是显示
But for the sake of simplicity,
但为了简明起见
we'll just treat that as part of
姑且把它当作是
the GPU.
GPU 的一部分
So in the very first frame, your
那么在第一帧里
app will try to get a drawable
你的应用会试图从
from the view.
视图中获取一个可绘制对象
And then from that drawable you
根据这个对象又可以
can get a texture and then start
获取一种纹理然后启动
a task to render to that
渲染该纹理的
texture.
任务
So once the CI gets that call,
在 CI 收到调用命令后
we will start encoding the
我们就要开始对
commands on the CPU for the work
完成 GPU 任务所用的
to be done on the GPU.
CPU 命令进行编码
And in this particular case,
单以这个例子来说
we're illustrating a filter
我们描画的是一个滤镜图表
graph that actually has multiple
实际上由多次滤镜处理
render passes, namely two
组成分别是两次
intermediate passes and a final
中间处理和一次
destination pass.
最终处理
Once Core Image has finished
当 Core Image 完成所有任务的
encoding all the work, the call
编码工作后对 startTask 的
to startTask will return.
调用便会返回执行结果
And then from then, that point
从这个时点开始
on the GPU will happily schedule
GPU 会很高兴地将
that work to be done at some
待执行任务安排在
appropriate time.
适当的时间段内
But, if the work on the GPU is
但是如果 GPU 的任务
going to take a long time, your
需要很长的时间才能完成
app could get called to render
你的应用可能会在上述任务
another frame before the work is
完成前就接到调用去渲染
done.
另一帧
And at that point, if you try to
此时如果你试图获取
get a drawable, that call to get
一个可绘制对象相应的
drawable will stall until it is
调用命令将会暂停直到它
ready to be vended back to your
可以被提供给你的应用时
application.
才会执行
And then only then can you get
这个时候你才能
the texture from it and start
从它那里获取纹理
another task to render to it and
启动另一项任务去开始渲染
then so on for all subsequent
后续的所有帧也会
frames.
重复同一过程
So, as you can see here, this is
所大家所见
not a very efficient use of both
这个过程对 CPU 和 GPU 的
the CPU and the GPU because
利用效率并不高
there's a lot of idle times on
两个处理器都存在着
both processors.
大量的闲置时间
But, if you look closely here,
但如果你仔细看下这部分
the drawable texture that we're
我们要渲染的可绘制纹理
about to render to is actually
实际上在最后一步的
not needed until the very last
渲染处理之前
render pass.
是用不到的
So let's look at how we can
那我们来看看
actually improve this scenario.
可以如何改进这个情况
So, with our new
使用我们最新的
CIRenderDestination API, you can
CIRenderDestination API
now initialize it, not with the
在初始化的时候
texture, per se, but rather, all
不必使用纹理本身
the properties of the textures,
而是纹理的所有属性
such as the width and height and
比如纹理的宽高
the pixel format of the texture.
像素格式
And then you can provide that
然后可以通过回调
texture via call back, which
提供该纹理而且会
will be called lazily at the
等到最后的最后
latest possible time for when
确实要用到该纹理的时候
that texture is actually needed.
才会真正调用
And so now, with the destination
于是现在你就能立刻
object initialized immediately,
完成目标对象的初始化
you can start a task and render
可以提前很多时间来
to it much sooner, and this will
启动任务和执行渲染
effectively defer that
这也会有效地推迟
potentially blocking call to
那个可能造成妨碍的
currentDrawable to a much later
currentDrawable 调用让它在
point in time.
更靠后的时点发生
So now, if we look at this
我们仔细看一下
example, the work now on the CPU
这个例子它能把CPU
and GPU can be pipelined much
和 GPU 的任务安排得
more efficiently.
更加高效
So if you're rendering to Metal
所以如果你要渲染 Metal
drawable textures, we strongly
可绘制纹理我们强烈
encourage you to use this new
建议你使用这款
API.
新出的 API
Because this could greatly
因为它能极大地
improve the frame rate of your
提高你的应用的
application.
帧率
In fact, we have seen cases
事实上我们看到过
where the frame rate literally
一些案例在运用了
doubled just by simply employing
这项技巧后帧率真的
this technique.
提高了一倍
All right.
好的
So now I'd like to hand it back
现在我要把讲台
to David who will tell you about
交回给 David 他会为大家
some really cool stuff that lets
讲解一些特别精彩的内容
you look under the hood inside
让大家一窥 Core Image 框架的
the Core Image framework.
个中奥妙
Thank you.
谢谢大家
&gt;&gt; Thank you so much Tony.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Tony
That's great stuff.
讲得很棒
As I mentioned in my
就像我在介绍的部分中
introduction, Core Image has a
提到的 Core Image 运用了
lot of great tricks it uses to
很多漂亮的技巧用来
get the best performance.
实现最佳的性能表现
And one of our goals this year
我们今年的一大目标
was to make it clearer to you,
就是让各位开发者大家
the developer, how those tricks
更清晰地了解这些技巧
are occurring so that you can
是如何发挥作用的好让大家
get a better understanding of
更好地理解应该
how to use Core Image
如何高效地使用
efficiently.
Core Image
And we've done that in a couple
在这方面我们采用了
of interesting ways.
两种有意思的方式
First of all, in our new APIs,
一种是利用我们新出的 API
we have some new ways of
我们设计了一些新方法
returning you information about
来返回你的
the render.
渲染器信息
After you've issued a task to
在你对渲染器发出
render, you can now, after when
任务指令后现在你可以...
you wait for that task to
在你等到任务完成后
complete, it will return a
该任务便会返回一个
CIRenderInfo object.
CIRenderInfo 对象
And this object will return to
这个对象又会为你
you an object with a few
返回一个附带少量
properties on it, including the
属性的对象包括
number of passes that Core Image
Core Image 执行这个
needed to use to perform that
渲染命令所需用到的
render.
处理次数
As well as the total amount of
以及在设备上
time spent executing kernels on
执行内核所耗费的
the device and also the total
总时间还有处理到的
number of pixels processed.
像素总数
So that's just a great piece of
所以你可以从
information that you can get
我们返回的信息中
when we return information to
获得十分丰富的信息
But perhaps what is even cooler
但也许更厉害的
is the awesome new editions
还是一些好用的新版本
we've made to Core Image to
我们现在可以让
provide better Quick Looks in
Core Image 在 Xcode 中
Xcode.
提供更出色的 Quick Looks
Notably, we now have a great
特别是我们现在为 CIImage
Quick Look support for CIImages.
提供了很棒的 Quick Look 支持
In addition to just showing the
除了显示像素外
pixels, we now show you the
我们现在还能显示你在
image graph that you constructed
生成图像的过程中
to produce that image.
构建的图像图表
If you do a Quick Look on a
如果你对一个 CIRenderTask
CIRenderTask, it'll show you the
执行 Quick Look 结果会显示出
optimized graph that Core Image
Core Image 对你的图像图表
converted your image graph into.
进行优化处理后的图表
And, if you wait for the render
此外如果你正在等候
info to be returned to you, if
渲染器信息的返回结果
you do a Quick Look on that,
此时对该进程执行 Quick Look 的话
it'll show you all the
结果将会显示
concatenation, timing, and
Core Image 内部发生的
caching information that Core
所有并置时间点以及
Image did internally.
缓存信息
So to give you an idea, we're
为了帮助大家理解
going to show you this in a very
让我们来用一种非常
visual way.
直观的方式为大家说明
Here's some code.
这里有一段代码
Let's pretend we're stepping
假装我们正在 Xcode 的
through this in Xcode.
环境中逐步调试这段代码
Here's an example of a image
这是一个例子
graph that we're going to
内容是我们准备构建的
construct.
图像图表
In this case, we're creating a
在这个例子里我们
CIImage from a URL, and we have
在创建一个 CIImage
a new option that we're
所用参数一个是 url
specifying on this image, which
一个是我们为
is
该图像指定的新选项
kCIApplyImageOrientationProperty
kCIApplyImageOrientationProperty
to true.
且赋值为真
And what this will do is
这段的作用是
automatically make the image
让图像在你面前
upright for you, which is a nice
自动直立起来这能
convenience.
带来很多便利
The next thing we're going to do
接下来我们会看到的
is we're going to add onto that
是要为这个图像
image an additional
另外增加一个
AffineTransform which scales it
仿射变换将图像
down by .5.
缩小为五分之一
Now imagine we're in Xcode, and
假设我们现在是在 Xcode 环境下
we hover over the image object.
将我们的鼠标悬停在图像对象上
And, if you click on the little
此时如果你点击这个
eye icon, it'll now pick up an
小小的眼睛图标它会显示出
image like this.
一幅这样的图像
In addition to the image showing
这幅图像不仅让你看到了
you what the image looks like
生成图像的观看效果
and it's nice and upright, it
图像清晰直立端正
also shows you the graph to
还能让你在它下方看到
create that image below it.
这幅图像生成过程的图表
If we zoom in, we can see all
如果把镜头拉近我们可以
sorts of interesting
看到各种有意思的
information.
信息
We can see, at the input of the
可以看到在图像图表的
image graph, we have our
输入端是我们的
IOSurface.
IOSurface
This is, I can tell by looking
仔细看一下会得知
at it it's a YCC image.
它是一幅 YCC 图像
It means it probably came from a
这说明它大概出自一个
JPEG, and you can see the size
JPEG 文件还可以看到
of that surface, as well as that
这个面的尺寸而且
it's opaque.
是不透明的
You can then see the next step
然后可以在图表接下来
above that in the graph is a
往上的第二步中看到
color-matching operation.
色彩匹配的操作
So we were able to determine
这让我们能够
automatically what the
自动确定输入图像的
colorspace of the input image
使用的是哪种
was.
色彩空间
And we've inserted it in the
然后我们将它插入
render graph and operation to
渲染图表及操作
convert from the display P3
从 P3 色彩空间显示
colorspace to Core Image's
转换到 Core Image 的
workingspace.
工作空间
And lastly, you can see three
最后可以看到
affine matrices.
三个仿射矩阵
The first one, as we're counting
从下往上数的
from the bottom, is the matrix
第一个矩阵是用来将
that converts from the image
图像的坐标系
coordinate system to the
转换为 Core Image
Cartesian coordinate system that
所使用的
Core Image uses.
笛卡尔坐标系
Then we have the affine to make
接着是一个仿射
the image upright, and then the
将图像放正
image affine to scale it down by
再接着是将图像
.5.
缩小为五分之一
So now you can really look at an
所以如今能让大家
image and see everything that's
仔细审视图像了解
being asked of it.
它接受过的所有操作了
Now let's do something slightly
现在我们再来做点
different this time.
不太一样的事情
Now we're going to ask for an
现在我们要请求获得
image, but we're going to ask
一幅图像不过这次是
for the auxiliary disparity
一幅视差补偿
image.
图像
And this is a new option that we
这也是我们这次推出的
have as well, and this, if your
一个新选项如果你的
image has depth information in
图像包含深度信息
it, it will return that as a
它便会以单色图像的方式
monochrome image.
返回该信息
After we ask for that image,
在我们请求完毕后
we're going to apply a filter on
我们要对它应用
it.
一个滤镜
In this case, we're going to
在这个例子里我们
apply a bicubic scale transform
要对它应用双三次缩放变换
to adjust its size.
来调整它的大小
Now, if we were to hover over
在 Xcode 环境下调试时
this object while we're
如果我们把鼠标悬停在
debugging in Xcode, we will now
这个对象上就能
be able to get this image.
得到这样一幅图像
And now you can actually see the
大家可以明确地看到
disparity image where white is
这张视差图像的前景
in the foreground and darker is
是白的在背景方向上
further in the background, but
越深颜色就越暗
we can also see the graph that
但我们还能看到
was used to generate this image.
这幅图像生成过程的图表
Here we see that the leaf or
像这里可以看到
input image is an IOSurface that
输入图像是一个 IOSurface
is a format luminance half
格式是亮度半浮点精度
float, and you can also see that
还可以看到
the dimensions of the image are
图像的尺寸
smaller than the original image.
要小于原始图像
You can also see at the top of
在这张图表的最上方
this graph the cubic upsampling
还能看到我们刚才应用
filter that we've applied.
的 cubicUpsample 滤镜
There's actually some method to
对于图表的显示用色
our colors that we chose here.
其实也是有规则可循的
One thing you'll notice is all
首先你会注意到
of the inputs to our graphs are
该图表所有的输入框
purple.
都是紫色
Anything that affects the color
任何会影响到图像
of an image, i.e., CIColorKernel
色彩的或者说 CIColorKernel
is red.
都是红色
Anything that affects the
任何会影响到图像
geometry, in other words, a
几何属性的或者说
CIWarpKernel, is green.
CIWarpKernel 都是绿色
And the rest of the kernels are
其余的内核
in a blue color.
全都是蓝色
So now let's get even more
让我们再来做点
interesting.
更好玩的事情
We're going to take the primary
我们打算取用一幅
image and we're going to apply
原始图像为它应用
two different color cubes to it.
两种不同的色彩立方体
We're going to take those two
然后分别取用得到的
resulting images and then we're
两幅图像再用一个
going to combine them with the
CIBlendWithMask 滤镜
CIBlendWithMask filter.
把它们合并成一幅图像
And, if we look at this in Quick
如果在 Quick Looks 里
Looks, we now see the final
查看这一串操作的结果
image where it's been
便能看到最后生成的图像
beautifully filtered with two
分别基于前景和背景
different effects, based on
经过两种不同效果的
foreground and background.
滤镜处理
But also, we see detailed
同时我们还能看到
information about the graph that
整个生成过程对应图表
was used to produce it.
的详细信息
You can see here, on the
大家可以看到
left-hand side, the portion of
在最左侧我们取用
the subgraph where we took the
输入图像对应的
input image, got the color cube
子图部分拿到了色彩立方体的
data, which is a 32 by 24 image,
数据一个 32x1024 的图像
and then apply that color cube
然后把这个色彩立方体
to it.
应用到了图像上
On the middle graph, we're doing
图表的中间部分
the same thing for the
我们是在对背景
background image.
做一遍相同的事情
All of these, plus the mask
所有这些再加上遮罩图像
image, are used to combine with
全部用 blendWithMask 内核
the blendWithMask kernel.
进行合并
So we're hoping that gives you
希望这些讲解让大家
great insight on how your
对于应用程序创建 CIImage 的
application creates CIImages.
过程有了很好的理解
But what happens when it comes
不过到了渲染这个环节
time to render?
又会发生些什么呢？
And this is where things get
这就是事情变得
really interesting.
有意思的地方了
Once you tell a CIContext to
在你告诉一个 CIContext
start a task, that'll return a
启动一项任务后这个过程
CIRenderedTask object.
会返回一个 CIRenderedTask 对象
This also supports Quick Looks.
这里同样支持 Quick Looks
And, if we look at this, we see
让我们来看一下
now an even more elaborate
显然这个图表的内容
graph.
更加详尽
Again, the color coding is the
同样这里的配色规则
same and we can see some of the
是一样的我们也能看到
same operations but now, what we
一些前面出现过的操作
saw before as a color matching
但是我们之前看到的
operation has been converted
色彩匹配操作
into the primitives that are
被转换成了
needed to do the color
执行色彩管理
management.
所需要的基元
So we can see that we needed to
我们可以看到我们需要
apply this gamma function and
应用这个 gamma 函数
this color matrix to convert
和这个色彩矩阵以便
from P3 to our workingspace.
从 P3 转换到我们的工作空间
Another thing you can see is,
大家还能看到
while the original image had
虽然原始图像经过
three affine transforms, Core
三次仿射变换
Image has concatenated those all
但 Core Image 已将三次
into one.
全部并置成了一次
Another thing you can notice is
还有一点大家会注意到的
at the end of the graph, we now
就是在图表要结束时
know what the destination
我们已经知道目标的
colorspace is.
色彩空间是什么了
So those operations have been
这些操作已经全部
applied to the image as well,
应用在图像上
both applying the colorspace as
全都经过了色彩空间
well as the coordinate system
和坐标系的转换
transform for the final
用以得出最后的
destination.
目标
You can also see it associated
大家还可以看到
with all these objects or all
所有这些对象或者说
the dimensions of all the images
渲染图表每一个环节所涉及到的
that are involved at each stage
所有图像的所有尺寸
of the render graph.
这里也全都有用到
Now, if you wait for your task
现在等到你给定的
to be completed, now there's a
任务完成后这里又
new object.
出现了一个新对象
And associated with this object
这个新对象会涉及到
is detailed information about
Core Image 是如何
how Core Image was able to
实现并置
concatenate and what the
以及渲染器性能的
performance of that render was.
详细信息
You'll see now there's much
大家也看到了这里的
fewer objects in the tree
树形图上出现的对象比较少
because of concatenation.
就是因为执行了并置
If we look at one of the lower
如果我们来看一下靠近
ones here, we can see that this
下方的地方会发现这有一个
particular program is the result
专门的 program 它就是
of concatenating a few steps
将几个步骤并置到
into one program, and we can
一段程序后得到的结果
also see associated with this
我们还能看到它用到的
the amount of time that was
参数还有这段程序执行起来
spent on that program in
所耗费的时间
milliseconds.
单位是毫秒
One great feature of Core Image
Core Image 有个很好的功能是
is, if you then render this
如果你接着又将
image again later and a portion
这幅图像渲染了一遍
of the graph is the same, then
渲染的图像部位也完全相同
Core Image may be able to obtain
那么 Core Image 能从
the previous results from a
缓存里调取上次的
cache.
处理结果
If that happens, then you'll see
发生这种情况的时候你会发现
the time go to zero in those
这里的所用时间
cases.
都变成了 0
So this also provides a way for
这也从另一个侧面
your application to know how
让大家了解到
efficiently Core Image is able
在给定的内存限制下
to render and cache your
Core Image 是如何高效地
results, given memory limits.
渲染和缓存结果的
So we hope you find this really
希望这能帮助大家
informative and instructional on
更具体也更清晰地了解
how Core Image works internally.
Core Image 的内部机制
The next subject I'd like to
我今天要讲的
talk a little bit about today is
下一个主题
barcodes, specifically the
是条形码确切说
CIBarcodeDescriptor API.
就是 CIBarcodeDescriptor 这个 API
We now have great broad support
我们的平台现在为条形码
for barcodes on our platform.
提供很出色的广泛支持
Barcodes of various different
不同类型的条形码
types from Aztec to Code128 to
无论是 Aztec Code128
QRCode and PDF417.
还是二维码  PDF417
We also have support for
我们还在多种不同的
barcodes across a broad variety
框架内支持条形码
of frameworks, and those
这些框架都对条形码
frameworks use barcodes in
有着不同方式的
different ways for good reasons.
合理运用
For example, oops, sorry.
比如说
AVFoundation is the framework to
AVFoundation 就是一种
use if you want to detect
在用摄影机拍摄
barcodes when you're capturing
视频时帮你检测
video from the camera.
条形码的框架
If you want to detect barcodes
如果你想要从
from either still images or from
静态图像或者
a video post-capture, the Vision
已摄视频中检测
framework is a great way of
条形码这个框架
using it.
会很好用
And lastly, you can use Core
最后大家可以使用
Image to render barcodes into
Core Image 将二维码
actual image files.
渲染成真正的图像文件
Given this broad support across
考虑到不同框架对二维码的
frameworks, we wanted to have a
广泛支持我们便想加入
new data type that would allow
一种新的数据类型
the barcode information to be
能让条形码信息
transported between these
在不同框架之间
frameworks in a lossless way.
无损传递
And that is the reason for the
于是我们就有了新推出的
new CIBarcodeDescription API.
CIBarcodeDescription API
There's one key property of this
这个对象只有一个
object, and that is the
重要属性就是
errorCorrectedPayload.
errorCorrectedPayload
This is not just the textural
它所包含的并不只是
message of a barcode.
一个条形码的文字信息
It's actually the raw data,
而是它的原始数据
which allows you to use barcodes
因而能让你通过
and get information out of them
单纯的文字信息以外的
in ways that are more than just
方式使用条形码
textural information.
从中获取信息
So, with this raw
利用包含原始数据的
errorCorrectedPayload and
errorCorrectedPayload
understanding of each barcode's
加上对每种条形码
formatting, you can do
格式的了解可以让你
interesting properties and build
基于二维码做出
interesting vertical
很有意思的功能打造出
applications based on barcodes.
有意思的垂直应用
Also there are properties that
此外每种条形码
are unique to each particular
也有一些自己独有的
barcode.
属性
For example, in the case of the
就拿 Aztec 条形码
Aztec barcode, you can know how
来说你可以获知
many layers were involved in
一个条形码包含了
that code.
多少个层
Or, in the case of the QRCode
再比如说二维码
barcode, what the maskPattern
就用到了所谓的
that was used on this.
掩码图案
So let me give you an example of
那么我来给大家举个例子
how this type can be used across
看看这个新的数据类型可以
these three frameworks.
如何在这三大框架下使用
So firstly, in the area of
首先要说的是
AVFoundation, it is possible to
AVFoundation
register for a
你可以注册一个
metadataOutputObjectDelegate
metadataOutputObjectDelegate
that will see barcodes, as they
它能看到输入视频中
are appeared in a video feed.
出现的条形码
In your code, all you have to do
而你在代码中要做的
is setup this object.
就是设置这个对象
And, in your response for when
在该对象检测到条形码时
that object is detected, you can
你可以在响应部分
ask for the object as a
将该对象以
AVMetadataMachine
AVMetadataMachineReadableCodeObject的
ReadableCodeObject.
名义调用
From that object, you can get
通过这个对象你可以
the descriptor property, and
获得 descriptor 属性
that will return one of the
这会返回其中的一个
CIBarcodeDescriptor objects.
CIBarcodeDescriptor 对象
Second if you want to use the
其次如果你想使用
Vision framework to detect
Vision 框架来检测
barcodes, the code is really
条形码所用的代码
simple as well.
也十分简单
Basically, we're going to use
基本上我们会使用
Vision to both create a request
Vision 创建请求处理器
handler as well as a request.
也会直接把它用作为请求
Then we're going to issue that
接着我们要将这个请求
request to the handler to detect
发送给处理器让它
the barcode.
去检测条形码
Once we get the request results
当我们收到返回的
back, we can then get the
请求结果后便可以
barcodeDescriptor object from
从结果中获取
that result.
barcodeDescriptor 对象
Very simple.
非常简单
And lastly, simplest of all, is
最后也是最简单的就是
using Core Image to generate a
用 Core Image 根据 descriptor
barcode image from a descriptor.
生成条形码图像
So, in this case, it's very
这种情况实现起来
easy.
特别简单
We just create an instance of a
我们只要创建一个
CIFilter of type
BarcodeGenerator 类型的
BarcodeGenerator.
CIFilter 实例
We then give that filter the
然后为这个滤镜提供
input of the descriptor object
descriptor 对象的输入
for the inputBarcodeDescriptor.
供 inputBarcodeDescriptor 使用
And then we're going ask for the
然后要求返回
output image.
输出图像
And these combined allow us to
这些技巧结合在一起
do some interesting stuff with
就可以让我们利用
both detection and generation of
条形码的检测与生成
barcodes.
做出有意思的东西
And so, as a brief prerecorded
这里有一段我们事先录制的
demo of this, let me show you a
演示视频给大家看一个
sample app that we wrote.
我们编写的示例应用
And what this does is look for
它的功能就是检查
frames of video, pulls the
视频的每一帧从中
barcode, and actually renders
拉取条形码然后渲染出来
the barcode back over the
再覆盖在视频中的
barcode as a -- kind of a
条形码上有点类似
augmented image over it.
某种增强图像
And you can see that we were
大家可以看到我们能够
able to perfectly reproduce the
完美地复制出
detected barcode and re-render
检测到的条形码并在它上方
it on top of it.
重新渲染出来
If we just see that again real
如果我们再来快速地
quickly, we can actually even
看一遍还可以发现
see that it's being render
这确实是渲染出来的
because overlapping my thumb in
因为它直接覆盖在了
the image.
我的大拇指上
So --
所以
All right.
好的
So for our last section of our
那么在今天这场讲座的
talk today, I'm really excited
最后一个部分里我很开心地
to talk about how to use Core
要跟大家讲讲如何将
Image and Vision together.
Core Image 和 Vision 结合使用
These are two great frameworks.
两者都是非常优秀的框架
Core Image is a great easy to
Core Image 能让你
use framework for applying image
很轻松地使用框架
processing to images.
对图像应用图像处理
Vision is a great framework for
Vision 则能让你
finding information about
非常方便地找到
images.
图像的信息。
And you can use those together
而这两者也可以通过
in great and novel ways.
便利且创新的方式结合使用
For example, you can use Core
比如说你可以将
Image as a way of preparing
Core Image 用作为
images before passing them to
将图像提交给 Vision 之前的
Vision.
预处理手段
For example, you might want to
再比如你或许
crop the image to an area of
想把图像按你的喜好
interest.
进行裁切
Or correctly make the image
或者将图像的角度
upright.
放端正
Or convert to grayscale before
或者在提交给 Vision 前
passing division.
转换为灰度图像
Also, once you've called Vision,
同样在你调用 Vision 后
once you have information about
在你获得图像信息后
the image, you might be able to
你也能将其作为
use that as a way of guiding how
调整图像
you want to adjust the look of
外观的
your image.
指导手段
So, for example, if a feature is
比如说如果在图像中
detected in an image, you might
检测到了某个特性
choose different ways to apply
你就可以选择不同的
image processing to it.
图像处理方式
And, of course, these two can be
这两者当然完全
combined together.
可以结合在一起
But to go into a little bit more
但为了讲得
detail about this.
更具体些
We have a interesting demo we'd
我们有个有趣的演示程序
like to talk about today, where
想跟大家探讨一下
we're going to try to generate a
我们会试着用
photo from several frames of the
视频的几个帧
video.
生成一张照片
Where the unwanted objects have
并将多余的物体
been removed from that.
从中删除
And this demo is going to
这段演示将会
involve using three frameworks
涉及三种框架
and four steps.
四个步骤
The first step is going to be
第一个步骤会
using AVFoundation to get the
使用 AVFoundation
frames out of the video.
提取视频的帧
And that's very simple to do.
这一步非常简单
Then we're going to use Vision
接着我们要用 Vision
to determine what the homography
来确定需要哪些
matrices are needed to align
单应矩阵来让每一帧
each of these frames to a common
依据共用参照系
reference.
进行校准
Inevitably there's some camera
一些相机抖动也是
shake, so a little bit of
在所难免所以一些
correction goes a long way.
校正处理也会大有益处
So that will allow us to get
于是我们便能得到
these homography matrices
这样一些单应矩阵
represented here as these
如屏幕所示画面的
slightly moving arrows for each
每一帧里都有这些
frame in the image.
位置会稍稍变化的箭头
The third step is to use Core
第三步是用 Core Image
Image to align all these frames
让所有这些帧
to each other.
参照彼此进行校准
And that's very easy to do, as
这一步也非常
well.
简单
And lastly, we're going to use a
最后我们要用
median technique to create a
求取中位数的办法
single photo from all the frames
根据视频中的所有帧
in the video in a way that
创建一张照片
produces an optimal image.
并且生成最佳的图像
The technique here is to produce
这里的技巧在于
an output image where, at each
生成一幅输出图像
location of the output, we're
在图像中的每一个输出方位
going to look at locations in
我们都要在输入帧中
the input frames.
查看相应的方位
And we're going to use the
然后我们会使用
median value at each location.
每个方位上的中位值
If you look in this example
大家看一下这个例子
here, the first four images are
前四幅图像里
that little spot is over the
小圆点都出现在
concrete pavement, but the fifth
水泥路上而在第五幅里
one is over the legs.
却出现在人腿上
Now, if we take the median of
如果我们对这五个值
these five values, we're going
求取中位数便可以
to get a value that looks like
得到一个看上去像是
just the concrete.
水泥路的值
If we do the same thing at
如果我们对图像中的
another portion of the image,
另一处区域进行同样的操作
again, we're here underneath the
得出的结果则是在
tree.
这棵树下
Three of the five frames are
这五帧中有三帧
good.
没问题
The other two are less good.
另外两帧就差一些
So we're going to use the median
所以我们要对它们
of those, and if you do that for
求取中位数而在对图像的
every pixel of an image, you get
每一个像素都如此处理后
a great result.
便能得到一个很好的结果
Where objects that are
所有在视频中
transitory in the video are
暂时出现的物体
magically removed.
全都被神奇地删除了
Let me talk a little bit about
现在让我先来多说几句
the code, and I promise we'll
这段代码我保证在最后
get to the demo at the end.
会让大家看到这段演示的
The first step here is we're
这里的第一步
going to use Vision to determine
我们要用 Vision
the homographic registration for
来确定每一帧的
each frame.
单应配准
Again, this is quite easy.
同样这也很简单
We're going to use Vision to
我们要用 Vision
create a request and a request
创建请求和
handler to produce that
请求处理器用来
information.
生成这些信息
We're going to tell Vision to
我们要告诉 Vision
perform that request.
执行这条请求
And then once we get the result,
然后在获得结果后
we'll ask for the result and
我们要返回结果
make sure it is an object of
并要确保返回的是
type VNImageHomographic
一个 VNImageHomographic 类型的
AlignmentObservation.
AlignmentObservation 对象
Wow, that's a mouthful.
啊好拗口
And then we'll return that.
于是我们就按要求返回
That object is basically a 3 by
这个对象基本上就是
3 matrix.
一个 3x3 的矩阵
Once we've returned that, we can
返回结果后我们便可
then use Core Image to align the
接着使用 Core Image
images based on this 3 by 3
依据这个 3x3 的矩阵
matrix.
校准图像
This is a little tricky, but
这部分需要点技巧
it's actually very easy to do
但如果使用 Metal 写成的
using a custom warp kernel
自定义 Warp 内核实现起来
written in Metal.
其实非常简单
You can see here in this kernel
大家可以在这个内核中看到
we now have a parameter which is
我们现在有个参数
a float3 by 3.
是个 3x3 的浮点数据
This is something that's new to
这是今年新增到
Core Image this year.
Core Image 中的
And what we're going to do is
我们要做的就是
we're going to get destCoord,
获取 destCoord
convert that to a homogenous
将它转换成单应性的
destCoord by adding a 1 to the
destCoord  办法是
end.
在末端加个 1
We're then going to multiply
接着我们要用
that vector by the matrix and
这个矢量与矩阵相乘
that gives us our
这会给出我们想要的
homogenousSrcCoord.
homogenousSrcCoord
Then we're going to do a
然后我们要进行一次
perspective divide to get us the
透视分割以便获取
source coordinate that we're
源坐标供我们
going to sample from.
采样用
And that's all there is to it.
这就是这部分的全部代码
The last step is to apply the
第三步是要用
median filter in Core Image,
Core Image应用中位数滤镜
and, in this example here, I'm
在现在这个例子里
illustrating the code that we
给大家看的是一段用来
use for a 5-image median.
对5幅图像取中位数的代码
In fact, sometimes you have many
事实上有时候你要处理的图像
more and we'll go into that
数量比这多得多我们会在
during the demo.
演示程序中再涉及这个问题
But, in this case, we're going
不过在现在这个例子里
to use a sorting network to
我们会用一个排序网络
determine what the median value
来求取五个像素样本的
of the five pixel samples are.
中位值
Again, if we look here, this is
同样大家留意一下这部分
a great example where writing
这是一个用 Metal 编写
this kernel in Metal was
此类内核的绝佳示例
actually very convenient and
又便捷又简单
easy, because now we can
因为如今我们在
actually pass the values into
将这些值传递给
this swap function by reference
这个 swap 函数时
rather than value.
可以按引用而非按值传递
So now for the fun part.
接下来这个有趣的部分
I'm going to invite Sky up to
我要请 Sky
the stage.
上台来
He'll be showing you more about
他会为大家讲解这个主题的
this and showing how this filter
更多细节以及这款滤镜的
works.
工作原理
&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt;  好的
Thank you, David.
谢谢 David
Hi, my name is Sky and it's a
嗨我叫 Sky
pleasure for me to bring to you
很高兴今天能为
today this demo.
大家带来这段演示
As we can see here on the top,
就像大家看到的画面上半部
this is our input in video.
是我们的输入视频
And, if I scrub around on the
我在滑条上来回刷动一下
slider, we can see that there's
我们可以看到
no point in time during the
在这一整段视频中
whole duration of the video that
没有任何一个时间点
there's a clear image that we
能让我们为这块地标
can take of the landmark.
提取出一个清晰的图像
So, for example, at the
所以就像这样
beginning, we're obstructed by
在一开始这里有
the shadow here.
影子把我们挡住了
And then we have people passing
接着又有路人
by.
来来往往
So there's really just no point
所以在整段视频中
during the entire video where we
完全没有一个时间点
can get a clean shot.
能让我们获得清晰的影像
And actually, if we zoom in on
实际上如果我们将镜头
one of the corners, we can see
拉近到它的一角处
that it's constantly shifting
便会发现整个视频期间
across the entire duration.
画面都在不停变化
So before we run the reduction
所以在我们运行 reduction 内核
kernel, we need to first align
之前需要先对这些帧
these frames.
进行校准
And the way we do that is using
我们的办法就是使用
Vision, as David just mentioned.
Vision  像 David 提到的那样
Now Vision offers two
现在 Vision可提供两个
registration APIs, as shown here
配准 API 滑条这里有
in the slider.
显示
We have a homographic line, and
其中一行字是单应性 (homographic)
which David just mentioned, but
也是 David 刚才提到过的
Vision also offers a
不过 Vision 还提供了一种
translational alignment which,
平移校准
in this case, doesn't work
以我们这个例子而言
extremely well.
效果并不太好
It's because our camera movement
因为我们的相机移动
is not restricted to one plane
并不是全部发生在一个
that is parallel to the image
与图像所在平面相平行的
plane.
平面上
So the way we're doing the
所以我们用来
stabilization is we're
稳定画面的办法
registering every frame during
就是将视频的每一帧
the video onto the middle frame.
都配准到中间帧上
And so you can expect a pretty
如此处理时不难预见
dramatic camera movement between
第一帧和中间帧的
the first frame and middle
相机位置变化非常之大
frame, which is why the
所以在这种情况下
homographic registration is
单应性配准
going to work better for us in
会给我们带来
this case.
更好的处理效果
So let's just go with that.
所以我们就用它处理
So with that turned on, if I
把这个操作打开后如果再把镜头
zoom in on this corner here
拉近地标的这个角这里
again and scrub through, you can
然后在滑条上刷动
see that the point is barely
你会发现这个点在每一帧中
moving across the entire frame.
基本都没有移动过
And if we go back and scrub
如果我们在滑条上反着刷回去
through, the video becomes
整个视频的画面
extremely stabilized.
也非常稳定
And so this gives you an idea,
这倒是让我们想到
if you're like writing an image
如果你打算写个
stabilization application, then
图像稳定应用
you could easily do that with
完全可以用 Core Image
Core Image and Vision.
和 Vision 轻松搞定
So now let me jump into the
接下来让我跳到
reduction part.
还原的部分
And the first thing I'd like to
这里我要指出的第一点
point out is doing a median
就是这里需要我们进行
reduction over what we have here
中位数还原处理的帧
is 148 frames.
共有 148 帧
It's not really that practical
这么做比较不切实际
because we need to hold all
因为我们在对它们
those frames in memory when
进行排序时需要把
we're sorting them.
所有帧都保存在内存中
So what we do here instead is we
所以我们这里的做法其实是
take the median of median as an
求取中位数的中位数
approximation.
作为一个近似值
So the first thing we do is
我们要做的第一件事
we're dividing entire frames,
就是将所有这些帧
the 148 frames, into several
148 帧划分为
groups.
几个组别
And for each one of those
然后对其中的每一个
groups, we compute a local group
组别都计算出一个
median.
局部的组别中位值
And on the second pass, we run
接着在第二道处理中
our reduction kernel again on
我们再对这些局部中位值
the local medians to compute the
运行 reduction 内核
final approximation results.
计算出最终的近似结果
Which is why we have this
于是我们在最下方这里
control here on the bottom, and
能看到这个控制条
these ticks here that shows you
还有这些按钮为你显示
how the frames are grouped.
这些帧的分组情况
And so, if I change this group
所以如果我改变一下这里的
count here, we can see that the
组别总数我们可以看到
indicators are changing.
这些指示器也会跟着变化
So, if we have a group count of
那么如果我们将组别数
three, that means we're dividing
设为 3 意思就是我们将把
the entire video range into
整段视频的所有帧划分为
three groups.
3 个组别
And for each one of those
对于每一个组别
groups, I can change the group
我也可以更改每组容量
size, which indicates how many
这个指标的意思是
evenly distributed tasks we're
我们会将所有帧平均
taking out of the frames to use
分配成一组多少帧
for our group median
以供我们计算
computation.
组别中位数之用
So, with that in mind, let's try
那么依照这些规则
something with a group count of
我们姑且将组别总数定为 5
five and group size of seven,
每组容量定为7
let's say.
先这样吧
And let's just see what that
让我们看看这会
gets us.
给我们怎样的结果
It's going to take a little bit
等它运行完毕需要
of time to run because Vision
一些时间因为 Vision
needs to do all the registration
需要完成所有的配准
and we need to warp the images.
我们还需要扭曲这些图像
And so, as we see here in the
那么就像我们在输出
output, none of the moving
这里看到的我们最后的
transient objects were actually
还原图像中没有出现任何
in our final reduced image, and
移动的暂时性的物体
we have a very clean shot of our
我们得到的地标照片
landmark, which is exactly what
非常干净完全符合我们
we wanted.
想要的结果
And, if we switch back between
如果我们在输入与
the input and the output, we can
输出之间来回切换一下
see that all textual details are
会发现整个文字细节都
very well preserved, which gives
保留得非常完美
you an idea of how well Vision
可以让你看到 Vision
is doing the alignment.
强大的校准能力
And so I hope this gives you a
希望这能给大家一些概念
sense of like the interesting
知道你们可以在 Core Image
applications you can build with
和 Vision 之间创造出
this nice synergy between Core
多么有意思的
Image and Vision.
协同效果
And with that, I'd like to
那么我要请
invite David back onstage and to
David 回到台上
give you a recap.
为大家做个总结
&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt;  好的
Well, thank you all so much.
非常感谢大家
Let me just give just a summary
让我来概括一下
of what we talked about today.
我们今天所讲的内容
Again, our primary goals for
还是那句话我们这个新版本的
this release was to give your
主要目标是为了让大家的应用
applications better performance,
实现更好的性能
better information about how
在 Core Image 的运行方面
Core Image works, and great new
获取更好的信息
functionality.
还有提供出色的新功能
And we really look forward to
我们十分期待看到大家
seeing how your applications can
应用利用这些新功能后
grow this year based on this new
会在今年实现
functionality.
怎样的成长
So we look forward to you coming
希望也能在我们的
to some of our related sessions.
相关讲座上见到各位
If you look -- need more
如果大家需要了解
information, please go to
更多信息请访问
developer.apple.com website.
网站 developer.apple.com
There are some related sessions
有一些相关内容的讲座
that are definitely worth
绝对值得大家
watching.
一看
There was a session earlier
今年早些时候也有一场讲座
today called image editing with
主题是支持深度的图像编辑
depth, as well as sessions on
还有几场介绍 Vision 框架的
Vision framework and sessions on
几场介绍支持深度的
capturing data with depth.
数据捕捉的
Thank you so much for coming and
感谢大家的参加
have a great rest of your show.
祝大家接下来也玩得开心
Thanks.
谢谢